

1321 Wilmot St #101, Ann Arbor, MI 48104 (734) 882-9855 • ttay@umich.edu https://ttay.me

### **SUMMARY**

Skilled C++ and Python programmer. I made a Python bot that schedules your Instagram posts for you.

Familiar with CMake, Linux, and GNU Coreutils (Make, grep, sed). I have worked on several side projects using C++ and am well-versed in optimizing programs for speed.

Quick problem solver experienced in working with large codebases. I fixed a rendering bug on my company's Python Flask application in just one day by **dissecting** the application into small components, **analyzing** the root cause using my experience, and **evaluating** the individual components to solve the problem.

### **EDUCATION**

#### UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN

Ann Arbor, MI

B.S. Computer Science, Honors Mathematics

September 2017 - Present

- Junior majoring in Computer Science and Honors Mathematics
- **Graduation Date (Expected):** May 2020
- **GPA:** 4.0/4.0 Awarded William Branstrom prize (2017) for academic excellence
- Course Highlights: Data Structures & Algorithms (281), Honors Linear Algebra, Graph Theory, Statistics

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN, COMPUTER AIDED ENGINEERING NETWORK

Ann Arbor, MI

Web Team Student Developer

May 2018 – Jun 2018

- Maintained the back-end of ParkIT, our web parking monitor app, using Python (Flask) and JavaScript.
- Author of the company's Python 3 tutorial, teaching OOP Python concepts for onboarding new hires.
- Wrote Python scripts for automated data processing to speed up University classroom allocation.

### RAFFLES INSTITUTION HIGH SCHOOL

Singapore

Teacher

Feb 2017 - Jun 2017

- Assessed and looked after 100+ high school juniors' progress over four months.
- Provided informative presentations and ensured that all students attained full comprehension.
- Planned a lesson timetable for 4 classes, ensuring that lessons adhered to curriculum objectives.

#### **COMPUTER SCIENCE SIDE PROJECTS**

# INSTAGRAM BOT [PYTHON]

(2018)

- Programmed a Python bot that schedules your Instagram posts, and automates liking and following.
- Created a full-stack web app using Python Flask and Bootstrap to allow users to schedule posts, providing a
  web-based drag and drop interface to easily see how posts are being scheduled.
- Used SQLite in the application backend database to keep track of user data.

#### POLYBAR - OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTOR [C++]

(2018)

- Augmented a module in Polybar, a 100% customizable status bar for the Linux OS with over 50k downloads.
- Implemented multithreading principles including mutexes, threads, and lock-guard in C++.
- Developed skills to comprehend large codebases (over 50k LOC) using vim and ctags.

## THREE SIBLING MATH PROBLEM SOLVER [C++]

(2018)

- Invented an algorithm in C++ to solve the three-sibling problem for N > 1000, a challenging math problem.
- Gained experience using CMake to perform out-of-source builds for large projects.
- Optimized the algorithm by 200% through efficient use of hash tables in caching results.

**Languages Experienced:** C++, Python

Worked with: JavaScript, Bash, SQL, Java, vimscript

**Toolbox** Git, CMake, Flask, NumPy, Pandas, ¡Query, SQLite, Bootstrap

For Fun Ballroom Dancing, Soldering, Arduino, Raspberry Pi